<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The ABS Language :: The ABS Modeling Language</title>
    <link>https://abs-models.org/index.html</link>
    <description>The ABS Language ABS is a language for Abstract Behavioral Specification, which combines implementation-level specifications with verifiability, high-level design with executablity, and formal semantics with practical usability. ABS is a concurrent, object-oriented, modeling language that features functional data-types.&#xA;ABS is designed to develop executable models with an object-oriented program flow ABS targets distributed and concurrent systems by means of concurrent object groups and asynchronous method calls ABS supports model variability based on delta-oriented specifications ABS supports deployment modelling based on high-level deployment models ABS supports a range of techniques for model exploration and analysis, based on formal semantics Overview</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 12:22:31 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://abs-models.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://abs-models.org/overview/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 12:22:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abs-models.org/overview/index.html</guid>
      <description>DESIGN PRINCIPLES OF ABS ABS targets the modeling of software systems that are concurrent, distributed, object-oriented, built from components, and highly reusable. To achieve the latter, we follow the arguably most successful software reuse methodology in practice: software product families or software product lines [35], see also the Product Line Hall of Fame. ABS supports the modeling of variability in terms of feature models as a first-class language concept. ABS thus provides language-based support for product line engineering (PLE).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://abs-models.org/getting_started/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 12:22:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abs-models.org/getting_started/index.html</guid>
      <description>There are various ways of running ABS models.&#xA;Use On-Line Tools The simplest way to use the ABS tools is on-line, in the collaboratory. This means you only need a modern browser to start experimenting with ABS. The tools work best with Firefox and Chrome.&#xA;An introduction and link to the collaboratory can be found at http://abs-models.org/laboratory/.&#xA;Installing Command-Line ToolsMany of the tools can be run from the command line. This page describes how to run various tools on a local machine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Documentation</title>
      <link>https://abs-models.org/documentation/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 09:16:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abs-models.org/documentation/index.html</guid>
      <description>The ABS language reference is the authoritative guide to what constitutes a legal ABS model, how to specify a Software Product Line, and how to use annotations to model time and resources.&#xA;There are some examples that walk through a small but complete ABS model to illustrate various modeling techniques.&#xA;We offer tutorials for the ABS language itself, as well as most tools that use ABS as an input language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications and Workshops</title>
      <link>https://abs-models.org/publications/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 12:22:31 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abs-models.org/publications/index.html</guid>
      <description>This page links ABS workshops, as well as selected research papers on the development and usage of the ABS modeling language and analysis tools.&#xA;ABS Workshops 2017 First International ABS Workshop: May 31–June 2, 2017, Oslo, Norway.&#xA;2018 Second International ABS Workshop: May 28–May 30, 2018, Darmstadt, Germany. https://formbar.raillab.de/en/abs2018/&#xA;2019 Third International ABS Workshop: May 13–May 15, 2019, Amsterdam, The Netherlands. https://www.cwi.nl/research/groups/formal-methods/events/third-international-workshop-on-the-abs-modeling-language-and-tools&#xA;2021 Fourth International ABS Workshop: August 26–August 27, 2021, Virtual.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://abs-models.org/contact/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 12:22:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abs-models.org/contact/index.html</guid>
      <description>We welcome bug reports and feature requests submitted via github at https://github.com/abstools/abstools/issues.&#xA;To contact the maintainers, post on the discussion form at https://github.com/abstools/abstools/discussions or write to abs-info@abs-models.org.&#xA;You can subscribe to the developers’ mailing list at the developer list manager page, or subscribe to a low-traffic announcement-only list at the announcement list manager page.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acknowledgments</title>
      <link>https://abs-models.org/acknowledgments/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 17:41:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abs-models.org/acknowledgments/index.html</guid>
      <description>Projects The development of the ABS language and tools has been supported by a number of research projects supported by the European Commission and the Research Council of Norway:&#xA;HATS: Highly Adaptive and Trustworthy Software using Formal Methods Envisage: Engineering Virtualized Services HyVar: Scalable Hybrid Variability SIRIUS: Enabling digitalization in and beyond the oil and gas industry Contributors The following people have contributed to the ABS language and tools so far:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Collaboratory</title>
      <link>https://abs-models.org/laboratory/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 13:34:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abs-models.org/laboratory/index.html</guid>
      <description>The Collaboratory is a browser-based IDE for ABS that offers an online, zero install version of the ABS toolchain. Use it to experiment with the language in a risk-free environment.&#xA;Load our ready-made examples or run your own ABS models. The editor has many features of an IDE, including showing you an outline of the code, and of course reporting syntax- and type errors.&#xA;The collaboratory also supports many of the analysis tools that we have developed, like COSTA and SACO.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>